Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Religion Serials TAM.777
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Religion Serials
1919-1999
1941-1999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM.777
3.8 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 2 flat boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Religion Serials contains over 90 titles published in the United States, Israel, Canada, and Europe on religious issues throughout the world between 1919 and 1999. The bulk of the collection consists of serials published between the 1940s and the 1990s by Jewish organizations in the United States.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to religion drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Religion Serials contains over 90 titles published in the United States (US), Israel, Canada, and Europe on religious issues throughout the world between 1919 and 1999. The bulk of the collection consists of serials published between the 1940s and the 1990s by Jewish organizations in the US on kibbutzim, Zionism, the study and use of Yiddish in the US, and human rights issues faced by Jewish people in the Soviet Union. These serials are mainly focused on cultural identity of Jewish people, rather than the religious aspects of Judaism. Religions represented in the collection in addition to Judaism include Catholicism; Islam; and Protestant sects including Methodist churches, Baptist churches, and Quakers. Other topics include community service, the work of inter-religious community organizations in the US, religious education and teachers, and atheism. Organizations represented in the collection include the Workmen's Circle, New Jewish Agenda, and the American Friends Service Committee.
Zionists -- United States.; Jews -- United States -- Societies, etc.; Jews -- United States -- Periodicals.; Religion and politics.; Serials (publications); Yiddish language -- Periodicals.
- A Majority of One: California Jewish Forum, Inc., Sherman Oaks, CA, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Action: Northwest Bronx Community and Clergy Coalition, Bronx, NY, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- AGC Reporter: Associated Gospel Churches, Wilkinsburg, PA, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Al Qalam: The Pen: Al-Qalam, Chicago, IL, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Ambijan Bulletin: American Birobidjan Committee, New York, NY, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- America: A Catholic Review of the Week: America Press, New York, NY, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- American Atheist: A Voice of Reason: Freethought Society of America, Inc., Honolulu, HI, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 27-28, Box 10, Folder 16)
- American Report: Clergy and Laymen Concerned, New York, NY, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Anglo Saxon World: British Israel Association of Greater Vancouver, Vancouver, BC, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Black International: Haldeman-Julius Publications, Girard, KS, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Bread is Rising: Emmaus House, New York, NY, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Bulletin: National Executive Committee of the Workmen's Circle, New York, NY, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Caribbean Contact: Caribbean Contact Ltd., Bridgetown, Barbados, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- CASA Maria Cry: Catholic Worker Movement, Milwaukee, WI, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Catholic Radical: Casa Maria Community, Milwaukee, WI, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Christian Crusade Weekly: Christian Crusade, Tulsa, OK, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 7-14)
- Christian News: Christian News, New Haven, MO, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Circleite: Workmen's Circle, New York, NY, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Commentary Report: American Jewish Committee, New York, NY, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Common Sense: Jewish Centers Association, Los Angeles, CA, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Community Relations Division Report: American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia, PA, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Congress Bi-Weekly: American Jewish Congress, New York, NY, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Converted Catholic Magazine: Christ's Mission, Inc., New York, NY, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Corporate Examiner: Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, New York, NY, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Digest: The National Conference on Soviet Jewry, New York, NY, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9-17)
- Encuentro: Kibutz Artzi, Tel Aviv, Israel, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Exegesis: Church of Nature, Dryden, MI, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Festivals: Resource Publications, Inc., San Jose, CA, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Firmest Bond: AL-URWA AL-WATHQA, Geneva, Switzerland, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Folk Un Zion: Executive of the World Zionist Organization, Jerusalem, Israel, Information Department, Jerusalem, Israel, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Freedom Magazine: Church of Scientology Western United States, Los Angeles, CA, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Genesis 2: Rebirth 2, Inc., Cambridge, MA, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
- Heritage: A Jewish Family Weekly: Heritage Publishing Company, Los Angeles, CA, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Horizons of Culture & Life: The Workmen's Circle, New York, NY, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- IFCO News: IFCO Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization, New York, NY, 1974-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8, Box 9, Folder 7)
- Information Bulletin: Va'ad Politi of Hashomer Hatzair, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Interfaith Council for Peace and Justice: Interfaith Council for Peace and Justice, Ann Arbor, MI, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Issues: American Council for Judaism, Inc., New York, NY, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- JDL & Soviet Jewry: Jewish Defense League, New York, NY, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Jewish Chronicle: Jewish Chronicle Newspapers Ltd., London, UK, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Josephite Harvest: Society of St. Joseph of the Sacred Heart, Baltimore, MD, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Kadima: Kadima, Seattle, WA, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Kadima: Jewish Student Association, Champaign, IL, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Kibbutz Journal: Kibbutz Aliya Desk, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- La Revue du FSJU (Le Fonds Social Juif Unifie): Imprimerie Chateaudun, Paris, France, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Little Way: Dorothy Day & Olive Branch Catholic Workers, Washington, DC, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Little Way: Dorothy Day Catholic Worker, Washington, DC, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Lumiere et Vie: Revue de Formation Doctrinale Chretienne: Saint-Alban-Leysse, Savoie, Lyon, France, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Material Aids Newsletter: American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia, PA, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Michael Fighting: Michael Fighting, Rougemont, Quebec, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Midstream: Theodor Herzl Foundation, Inc., New York, NY, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Militant Truth: Christian Citizens Crusade, Inc., Atlanta, GA, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Morim Newsletter of the J.T.A.: Jewish Teachers Association, New York, NY, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Motive: Board of Education of The United Methodist Church, Nashville, TN, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
- Motive: Division of Higher Education of the Board of the United Methodist Church, Nashville, TN, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Motive: Methodist Student Movement / Motive, Inc., New York, NY, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Na'amat Woman: Na'amat USA, New York, NY, 1989-1996 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- National Christian News: National Christian News, St. Petersburg, FL, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- National Laymen's Digest: National Laymen's Council of the Church League of America, Chicago, IL, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- NAWR Trends: National Assembly of Women Religious, Chicago, IL, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- New Jewish Agenda: New Jewish Agenda, New York, NY, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- New Jewish Agenda: New Jewish Agenda - Manhattan Chapter, New York, NY, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- New Jewish Times: A Journal of Planetary Renewal: The Martin Steinberg Center for Jewish Artists, New York, NY, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- News & Views: National Laymen's Council of the Church League of America, Wheaton, IL, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Newsletter: Religious Society of Friends, New York, NY, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Newsletter: Jama'a-tul Muslimiin, Brooklyn, NY, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Nitzotz: Radical Zionist Alliance, New York, NY, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Opinion - A Journal of Jewish Life and Letters: Jewish Opinion Publishing Corporation, New Haven, CT, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Origins: Catholic News Service, Washington, DC, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Other Americans: Other Americans, Baltimore, MD, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Parents' Bulletin: Education Department of the Workmen's Circle, New York, NY, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Pendle Hill Bulletin: Society of Friends, Wallingford, PA, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Politics of People: Department of Church in Society, Canada, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Post American: People's Christian Coalition, Chicago, IL, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
- Post American: People's Christian Coalition, Deerfield, IL, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 20-22)
- Protestant: Protestant Digest, Inc., New York, NY, 1943-1949 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Radix: Davenport Catholic Worker Houses, Davenport, IA, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Report: Mennonite Central Committee, Akron, PA, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Report: American Jewish Alternatives to Zionism, Inc., New York, NY, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 4-8, Box 6, Folder 11)
- Response: Jewish Student Press Service, New York, NY, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Settler: Haikar Haoved / Moshav Movement, Tel Aviv, Israel, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Shalom Network Newsletter: New Jewish Agenda, New York, NY, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Sharing Principles: American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia, PA, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Social Action in Review: Union of American Hebrew Congregations, New York, NY, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Social Order: Institute of Social Order, Saint Louis, MO, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- SQB: Methodist Federation for Social Action, Staten Island, NY, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Truth Seeker: Truth Seeker Company, New York, NY, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Unser Tsait: Atran Center for Jewish Culture, New York, NY, 1963-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8-13, Box 6, Folder 1)
- Voice: The Cathedral School Newsletter: Cathedral School of St. John the Divine, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3, Box 9, Folder 25)
- Voice for Human Rights: Committee of Catholics for Human Rights, New York, NY, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Witness: Episcopal Church Publishing Company, Ambler, PA, 1983-1991 (Box 6, Folder 3-10)
- Witness: Episcopal Church Publishing Co., Detroit, MI, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- World Fellowship: World Fellowship of Faiths, New Haven, CT, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Yiddisher Kaempfer: Der Yiddischer Arbeiter, New York, NY, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Yiddisher Kemfer: Labor Zionist Letters, Inc., New York, NY, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 6-8, Folder 10-13)
- Yiddisher Kemfer: Waldon Press, Inc., New York, NY, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Zionist Independent: Universities Zionist Council of Great Britain & Ireland, London, UK, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)